ALI NEHME, Ph.D.

Full Stack Developer

Brossard, Canada

SUMMARY

A soon to graduate Full Stack Developer with a passion for developing scalable and complex applications. Backed up with data science experience and a diverse set of soft skills from 10 years of scientific research as a computational biologist. Always strive to bring 100% to the work I do. I look forward to joining a creative and hard-working team where I can grow my skills while pushing projects to success.

Available starting from January 2, 2023.

SELECTED PROJECTS

ChatApp

09/2022

A messaging app/forum similar to Discord with rooms and live messaging.

- Frontend: React.js and CSS / Backend: Node.js and socket.io / Database: MySQL
- Role: authorization, live messaging, database management, profile management
- https://github.com/nehmea/2022-WDII-chatApp

Commons

m 08/2022

A website that can serve as a platform for people to share their possessions.

- Frontend: Thymeleaf, Bootstrap / Backend: Java Spring Boot / Database: MySQL
- Role: project skeleton, database management, authentication and authorization
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

HomingPigeon



A commercial website for selling postcards.

- Frontend: PHP, HTML, and CSS / Backend: PHP / Database: PhpMyAdmin
- Role: products page (add to favourites & cart), product info, profile management
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

Bookstore Library

₩ 05/2022

A REST API that stores information on books and users, and represent them to users.

- Frontend: JS, HTML, Bootstrap / Backend: Java Spring Boot / Database: MySQL
- Role: I developed the whole API (solo project)
- https://github.com/nehmea/JAC_FSD_WS_Bookstore

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Principal Mentor

STEM-Away

· Designed workshops and oversaw educative projects in bioinformatics.

Computational Biology Consultant

Freelancing

₩ 09/2019 - Ongoing

· Helped private and academic teams design projects and perform analysis.

Postdoctoral Researcher in Cancer Genomics

McGill University

1 09/2018 - 08/2020 Montreal, Canada

- Designed a workflow to analyze spatial transcriptomics data.
- Assisted colleagues and collaborators on eight projects with bioinformatics analysis on RNA-seq, scRNA-seq, and spatial transcriptomics data.

Postdoctoral Researcher in Molecular and Computational Biology

University of Tours

1 09/2016 - 06/2018

Tours, France

- Designed a workflow for horizontal integration of transcriptomics datasets.
- Delivered results on 12 projects using computational and bench methods.
- Initiated a project for biomarkers discovery and prognostic score development in AML using data science and machine learning models.

LANGUAGES

English

French

Arabic

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks

React	Java Spring	g Boot	.NET	core
ASP.NET	WPF	Razor P	ages	jQuery
Socket IO	JPA	Sequelia	ze	

Frontend

JavaScript	XAML	HTML	CSS	

ThymeLeaf

Backend

Java	NodeJS	PHP	Python	R	C#

Database

MySQL	MSSQL	phpMyAdmin	Sqlite
-------	-------	------------	--------

Hosting

AWS EC2	AWS RDS	XAMPP

Project Management

Github	Microsoft Office	Trello

Data Science

Data Wrangli	ing	Visualization	Regression
Clustering	PCA	Hypothesi	s Testing

SOFT SKILLS

Presentation Self-learning Flexiblity

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer (A.E.C., 1035 hours, Average 95%)

John Abbott's College

01/2022 - Ongoing

Ph.D. in Bioinformatics and Pathophysiology

Claude Bernard University Lyon 1

11/2015 11/2015

TRAINING / WORKSHOPS

The Data Science Course 2022: Complete Data Science Bootcamp

Udemy, Ongoing

Introduction to the Unix Shell

Calcul Quebec, September 2020